Manar Ajhar Software Developer

manarajhar93@gmail.com • +971-50-988-7983 • LinkedIn Residence: Sharjah, the United Arab Emirates • Nationality: Canadian



Professional Summary

Skilled game developer with 5+ years of experience in software programming. Very proficient in using C#, C++, Java, and Unity. Other acquired skills include augmented reality (AR) programming, artificial intelligence (AI) programming, and game development. Capable of developing many games and apps using AR and AI.

Areas of Expertise

- C++
- AR Programming
- Communication Skills
- C#
- Al Programming
- Mobile Programming
- Java
- Unity
- Problem-Solving Skills

Experience

Educational Game for Asthmatic Children October 2023 - Present

Developing a game for smartphones using Unity to educate children about asthma. The game utilized Augmented Reality.

Mobile Game Application

January 2018 – August 2018

Developed a multiplayer game for iPhone X with a team. The game had Augmented Reality and Networking.

First-Person Shooter Game

September 2015 – May 2016

Developed a First-Person Shooter game for PCs using Unity. The game had AI elements.

Education

Master's Degree

Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada

Post-Graduate Degree

Sheridan College, Oakville, Ontario, Canada

Bachelor's Degree

University of Sharjah, Sharjah, UAE

September 2021 – June 2023

September 2017 - October 2018

September 2013 – January 2017

Additional Experiences

Intern

Newcastle University, Newcastle Upon Tyne,

July 2015 - August 2015